[{"question":"<p><strong>Representative democracy is best characterised by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Free elections and proper registers of voters","A politically educated electorate","Rule by the interest group","Proper constituencies and a real choice of candidates"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>While political partial parties aim at forming a&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>government, pressure groups aim at<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Causing social unrest","Influencing governmental decisions","Controlling nation\u2019s economy","Getting workers to unite"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>When the electorate vote for representatives who in <\/strong><strong>turn vote on their behalf we say it is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["An indirect election","An unfair election","A disputed election","A rigged electron"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>An election which is conducted to fill a vacant seat in a<\/strong><strong> legislature is called a<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bye-election","General election","Referendum","Plebiscite"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these countries does NOT operate a federal<\/strong><strong> constitution?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["USA","Nigeria","Canada","France"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major advantage of the secret ballot is that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It is faster than other systems","Nobody can be prevented from voting","It ensures the anonymity of each voter","Losers can ask for another secret voter"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a one party state<\/strong><\/p>","options":["There are no free citizens","The communist party is the only legal party","The ruling party is the only legal party","Elections to be legislature are held at the party\u2019s conferences"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cabinet system of government is practiced in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Britain and Canada","The soviet union","All European Countries including Britain","The United State of America"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A proclamation by the head of state ending a session<\/strong><strong> of parliament is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A dissolution","An adjournment","A prorogation","A devolution"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The constitution of the federal republic of Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Promotes unity of diversity","Allows for the dominance of the minority ethnic groups","Concentrates governmental power at on one level of government","Ensures the dominance of one political party"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The transfer of authority to local government council<\/strong><strong> is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Delegation","Fusion","Fragmentation","Devolution"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The principle of anonymity of civil servants means<\/strong><strong> that they<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are not the servant of a particular government","Are trained for the duties they perform","Are credited or blamed for any thing they do","Have a career"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The six registered political parties in Nigeria in 1982<\/strong><strong> were<\/strong><\/p>","options":["UPN, NPN, PPA, PPP, NPP, and NAP","UPN, GNPP, NAP, PRP, NPP, NPN","NPN, UPN, NPP, PRP, PPP NNDP","NPC, GNPP, PRP, UPN, NPP and PPA"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a pressure group in<\/strong><strong> Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Farmers","the Nigerian union of teachers (NUT)","Nigeria medical associate (NMA)","Academic staff union of university (ASUU)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The N.C.N.C sent a delegation to London in 1947 to<\/strong><strong> protest against the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Burns constitution","Richards constitution","Littleton constitution","Macpherson constitution"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A popular principle of colonial administration in British W<\/strong><strong>est Africa was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Association","Indirect rule","Paternalism","Assimilation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first governor-general of colonial Nigeria was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sir Hugh Clifford","Sir James Robertson","Lord Lugard","Sir Ralph moore"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first military government in Nigeria was headed<\/strong><strong> by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["General Yakubu Gowon","General Agunyi Ironsi","General M. Mohammed","General O. Obasanjo"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first general election in Nigeria was hold in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1933","1952","1955","1959"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"}]